valueappeal.com 2017-11-05

# Porch | Privacy

Effective Date 10/19/2016

Your privacy is important to us and we are committed to protecting your information in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

## Overview

This Privacy Policy describes the collection, use and disclosure of information by Porch.com, Inc. (“Porch”, “we,” “us”) and other parties with respect to your use of all properties (Web sites, mobile application, telephone service or otherwise) owned or operated by Porch and our affiliates (collectively, the "Properties"), and all products and services available from Porch, home improvement service providers (“Pros”) or other third parties in connection with the Properties (individually and collectively with the Properties, the “Services”). By accessing or using the Services, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Services.

All capitalized terms used but not defined in this Privacy Policy have the meanings given in our Terms of Use (located here). References to "you" mean you as a User and/or as a Pro, as the case my be. References to Porch (or “we” or “us”) also include Porch’s service providers and partners, to the extent that such service providers are collecting, using or disclosing information for or on behalf of Porch.

## Privacy Policy Updates

We may update this Privacy Policy at any time by posting a revised version. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will be effective immediately upon posting. Please review this Privacy Policy each time you use the Services, as your continued use of the Services after such changes will constitute your acceptance and agreement to such changes.

## Collection of Information

 **Information You Provide**

 _Information You Submit._ As a User, you can visit and browse the Properties without opening an account and entering personal information. You will need to open an account if you would like to get a quote for home services or if you are a Pro. When using the Services, whether as a User or as a Pro, you may elect to provide information about yourself, such as name, address, telephone number, email address, payment details and information about your use of the Services or your experiences with Porch, Pros, or Users. You may provide this information, for example, when you create an account, post User Submissions, request or purchase products or services, communicate with us, a Pro, or a User, subscribe to our email programs, “Like” us on Facebook or otherwise connect us to your social networks, or complete other forms. If you are a Pro, you may provide additional information about yourself or your company, including for example, when you provide details to complete your account, respond to service requests, and provide information for background/reference checks.

In connection with the Services, you may also elect to provide reviews, comments, feedback, notes, photos, videos, know-how, techniques, or other information relating to you, your project, your household, your business, your real or personal property or otherwise.

 _Social Networks._  If you use the social networking connection functions offered through the Services, we may access any of your social profile information that you have made available to be shared and to use it in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Please refer to your social network policies to manage information that is shared through that account.

 **Information We Collect Automatically**

 _Cookies and Web Beacons._   We, our service providers and our advertising networks use cookies, web beacons (sometimes called single-pixel gifs or action tags) or similar technologies on the Properties, in emails and in advertisements to collect information about your online activities. Cookies (small data files that your Internet browser stores on your hard disk or in your browser's memory) are used by the Services to connect your activity on the Services with other information we store about you in your account profile or from prior usage of the Services. Web beacons are electronic images that assist in delivering cookies, provide additional information (such as which ad you clicked on to arrive at the Properties) and allow us to compile aggregated statistics. For example, the use of cookies allows us to improve our Services by tracking saved searches, understanding your and other site visitors’ use of various features and functionality, delivering targeted ads that are more relevant to you, avoiding ad duplication, measuring the effectiveness of advertising and otherwise creating a consistent user experience for you. Collected information may include the content you view, the date and time you view content, and the referring web site or advertisement. This information may be associated with your unique browser, device identifier or IP address.

At any time, you may adjust your browser settings to delete existing cookies (and the data that web beacons add to the cookie), or refuse new cookies, according to the method permitted by your browser. If you choose to delete cookies, you will need to log in again on your next visit to the Properties and re-enter any preferences you have set. If you choose to disable cookies, you may not be able to access or use some portions and features of the Services and may not get the best experience possible.

Your browser may offer you a "Do Not Track" option, which allows you to signal to operators of websites and other properties that you do not wish such operators to track certain online activities. Our Services do not support Do Not Track requests at this time.

 _Log Usage Data._  Our servers automatically record usage log data created when you use the Services. Usage log data may include information such as your IP address, browser type, operating system, referring web page, visited web pages, location, mobile carrier, computer or mobile device type, search terms and cookie information.

 _Location Data._  If you provide location information during the account registration process or at any other time via your account settings, or if location information is included as part of the information we collect (for example, your IP address may provide an approximate geo-location), we may store that information in connection with your account. If you are using mobile Services, we may collect location data directly from your mobile device if your device allows us to do so. Your mobile device manufacturer or mobile service provider may provide you with choices about how and whether location data is shared with us.

 **Other Information We Collect**

 _Telephone Calls._  When you call us, when we call you, or when we forward calls between Users and Pros, we may monitor and/or record those calls for quality assurance and customer satisfaction purposes. In those jurisdictions where consent is required for a party to record a telephone call, you consent to us recording such calls.

 _Email and Mobile Content Programs._ You can choose to receive promotional emails from us. Like most e-commerce sites, we include software code in our emails to monitor whether and when you opened the email, whether you have clicked on the images and/or links in the email, and whether your computer or mobile device is capable of receiving HTML-based email. You may also choose to access our content through a mobile application and to receive text messages on your mobile device. You may opt out from email and mobile programs as described below under "Opting Out.”

 **Information Collected by Third Parties**

 _Online Activity._ You may get cookies or web beacons from our advertisers, tracking utilities, partners or other third parties with links on the Properties. While this is a standard practice in the industry, we have no control or access to these cookies or web beacons. Our Privacy Policy does not cover the use of these technologies by third parties or the use of such technologies on websites or mobile applications other than the Properties.

 _Offline Activity._  Porch and Pros may collect text, photos, videos, measurements, comments, reviews, feedback, notes, ideas, know-how, techniques, data or information of any nature whatsoever relating to you, your household, your real or personal property or otherwise, in connection with the Services provided by Porch or the services provided by Pros.

 **Information We Obtain From Third Parties**

We may obtain information about you from third parties and use it to provide a customized experience, to offer products or services that might be of interest to you, to supplement or correct information that you have provided to us, and generally to improve our Services.

 **Aggregate Information**

We collect non-personal, statistical information about the use of the Services, such as how many visitors visit a specific page, how long they stay, and which links they click on. We may also group and de-personalize information into aggregate visitor data in order to describe and analyze Services usage.

Information collected on the Properties may be combined with other personal or aggregate information, including information we collect by other means (for example, if you call or email us). The combined information will also be subject to this Privacy Policy.

## Use of Information

Any information we collect from you may be used in the following ways:

  * To provide the Services;
  * To improve the Services (for example, to personalize your experience to make it smoother and more relevant to you, and to improve the content and design of the Properties;
  * To process transactions, to provide and improve customer service, and to otherwise manage our customer relationships;
  * To connect Users with Pros and other companies that receive or help us meet service requests;
  * To connect Pros with Users, to help Pros select with whom they choose to work and to provide Pros with more opportunities to receive service requests that might be of interest to them;
  * To provide you with information about products and services from Porch and our partners that may be of interest to you, and to optimize our and our partners’ marketing campaigns;
  * To provide you with complementary product and services that may be of interest to you, including discounts and other benefits from our partners;
  * To administer contests, promotions or sweepstakes;
  * To prevent fraud and abuse, to comply with applicable laws and legal process, to address technical and security issues, to comply with applicable laws and legal process, and to otherwise protect Users, Pros, and our business;
  * To develop and deliver our advertising, products and services and analyze their effectiveness; and
  * To perform other functions described at the time the information is collected.

## Disclosure of Information

Information that you choose to provide in a public area of the Services (such as your profile page or via User Submissions) will not be protected by this Privacy Policy because you have chosen to make that information public. Otherwise, your information and aggregate information will be shared with third parties only in accordance with this Privacy Policy, as follows:

 **Consent**

We may share your information when you consent or direct Porch to do so. For example, if a User seeks a Pro through the Services, we may provide User information to the Pro and Pro information to the User. The method of consent will be appropriate for the type of personal information involved and the purposes for which it is collected, used or disclosed. Depending on the circumstances, consent may be express (i.e., you specifically agree either verbally, in writing or electronically) or implied.

 **Please note that, when you submit a request for products or services, you are requesting to be (and you expressly consent to be) contacted by Porch, companies that receive your service request, and Pros, as the case may be. You consent to be contacted by these parties by telephone, email, mail, text (SMS) messaging, fax, or other reasonable means at any of the residential, cell or fax phone numbers or addresses you provide, even if they are listed on a national "do not call" or “do not contact” list. You agree that these communications may include prerecorded, artificially voiced or autodialed telemarketing messages, and that they may be monitored and recorded for quality assurance and other reasons. You agree that these parties may contact you for the purposes of providing the products or services you have requested, marketing, addressing complaints, billing or other account-related matters, or other purposes reasonably related to the services you have requested. Your consent to receive marketing communications is not required as a condition of purchasing any goods or services.**

 **Service Providers**

We contract with other companies to provide services on our behalf. For example, we may use third-party service providers to process payments, host the Properties, provide call center or other customer service, send out information or offers, serve or manage ads, and analyze Services data. Some of these companies collect and store information for us as part of their services, or we may provide them with the elements of your personally identifiable information that they need to deliver their services. These companies are prohibited from using personally identifiable information for any other purpose and will have access only as necessary to perform the applicable services for us.

 **Co-Branded Partners**

Some of our Services may be offered in conjunction with a third party. If you access or use our Services through a third party, or you access or use a third party’s services through the Properties, both Porch and the third party may receive information provided by you or collected in connection therewith. For example, If you sign up with Porch through a Lowe's-promoted or co-branded website or within a Lowe's store, Porch and Lowe’s may share your information with each other.

 **Other Partner Programs**

From time to time, we may partner with third parties to offer discounts, rewards or other programs or promotions. We may disclose the personal information of the participants in the programs to those business partners. For example, if a discount is offered through a link between their website and our website, we may disclose information about our Users that visit their website or their users who visit our website. We will disclose your personal information to those business partners when you consent to that disclosure, including consent implied by your agreement to the applicable program rules.

 **Pro Information**

We may share a Pro’s business name, owner/proprietor name, business contact information and other information with third parties.

 **Compliance with Laws and Policies; Protection of Rights**

We may release your information (including personally identifiable information) and aggregated information when we believe that doing so is appropriate to comply with applicable laws, regulations, subpoenas, warrants or court orders, or other legal requirements; to cooperate with government or law enforcement; to resolve complaints or disputes; to avoid legal liability; to comply with, enforce or investigate potential violations of our agreements, Terms of Use, Privacy Policy or other policies; to bill and collect amounts owed to us; to protect our rights, reputation, safety or property or that of Users or others; and to address fraud, security or technical issues.

 **Sale/Merger**

We may decide to sell, buy, merge or reorganize our own or other businesses, conduct a securities offering, or do a joint venture or other strategic transaction. We could also be involved in a bankruptcy, liquidation, dissolution or similar transaction. Any such transaction may involve disclosing personal and other information. We would seek protections of confidentiality and restricted use for all information disclosed. In the event that we or all of our assets are acquired in such a transaction, our collected information would be one of the transferred assets.

 **Contest/Sweepstakes**

We may publicly disclose the name, city and state of winners.

 **Aggregate Data**

We may share aggregated, non-personal data with service providers, advertisers or existing or potential business partners.

## Opting Out; Editing Your Personal Information

 **Changing Information; Closing Account**

To change or delete your information, you may login to your account and modify or remove specified information that resides in your account. If you want to delete your account, please contact us at [questions@porch.com](mailto:questions@porch.com). We will remove your account within a reasonable time after receiving your request. Please note that, even after your account is deleted, information that you chose to provide in a public area of the Services (such as reviews and projects) will remain visible to the public and may remain in the accounts of Users and Pros with whom such information has been shared, and all of your information will remain in Porch’s backup/archival records. Porch may retain and use information in our records as described in this Privacy Policy, including but not limited to the section entitled “Disclosure of Information/Compliance with Laws and Policies; Protection of Rights,” above.

You may also make requests regarding your personal information, such as requests to access information or requests to update or correct inaccurate information, by emailing us at [questions@porch.com](mailto:questions@porch.com) or writing us at 2200 1st Avenue South, Seattle, WA 98134.

 **Email Programs**

You may unsubscribe at any time from our email programs by clicking on the unsubscribe link included at the bottom of every email message or by sending a request to [questions@porch.com](mailto:questions@porch.com). We reserve the right to send you service announcements (such as notifications about site outages) or administrative messages, without offering you the opportunity to opt out of receiving them. In addition, because we must communicate with you about service requests that you have submitted (or received, if you are a Pro), you cannot opt out of receiving emails relating to those requests.

 **Direct Mail**

You may opt out at any time from receiving direct-mail promotional correspondence by sending a request to [questions@porch.com](mailto:questions@porch.com).

 **Mobile Programs**

You may opt out of a specific mobile messaging campaign by texting “stop”. Text "stop all" to opt out of all mobile messaging.

## Your California Privacy Rights

Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code permits California residents to request from a business, with whom the California resident has an established business relationship, certain information about the types of personal information the business has shared with third parties for those third parties' direct marketing purposes and the names and addresses of the third parties with whom the business has shared such information during the immediately preceding calendar year. You may make one request each year by emailing us at [questions@porch.com](mailto:questions@porch.com) or writing us at 2200 1st Ave South, Seattle, WA 98134.

## Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. We maintain industry-standard physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards, such as firewalls and encryption technology, to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. For example, when you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on the Properties, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer (SSL) technology. However, no method of transmitting information over the Internet or storing information is completely secure. Accordingly, we cannot guarantee the protection of any information shared with us.

If you create an account, you may be asked to choose a password to protect your account and account information. We recommend that you do not disclose your password to any other person. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your password and account, and are fully responsible for all activities that occur under your password or account.

## General Matters

 **Children**

The Services are not directed to children under 13, and we do not knowingly collect or store any personally identifiable information about persons under the age of 13. If we learn that we have collected personally identifiable information of a child under 13, we will make commercially reasonable efforts to delete such information from our files. If you are under the age of 13, please do not submit any personal information through the Properties.

 **Third-Party Websites**

Our Services may contain links to other websites and services. Any information that you provide on another website or service is provided directly to the owner or operator of the website or service and is subject to that party's privacy policy. In addition, if you visit the Properties through a link or advertisement on another website, then that website may be collecting information from users who click on the link or banner, and the collected information will be subject to that website’s privacy policy. Our Privacy Policy does not apply to any such websites or services, and we are not responsible for their content, privacy or security practices and policies. To protect your information we recommend that you carefully review the privacy policies of other websites and services that you access.

 **Governing Law; Visitors Residing Outside the United States**

All of the Services are hosted in the United States. This Privacy Policy and the privacy practices of our Site will be subject exclusively to the laws of the State of Washington within the United States of America, without regard to conflict of law principles. If you reside outside of the United States, you are responsible for complying with local laws in connection with your use of the Services, and you consent to the collection, transfer, storage, and use of your personal information in the United States of America in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

 **Porch Terms of Use**

Your access or use of the Services is subject to Porch’s Terms of Use (located here).

 **Contacting Us**

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our Privacy Policy, please contact us by email at [questions@porch.com](mailto:questions@porch.com) or in writing at 2200 1st Ave South, Seattle, WA 98134.
